californiawatch.org 2011-11-02

# Privacy Policy | California Watch

###### California Watch Terms of Use and Privacy Policy

This site is published by the Center for Investigative Reporting, a tax-exempt 501(c)3 organization located at 2130 Center Street, Suite 103, Berkeley, California 94704.

By accessing this site, you agree to be legally bound by and comply with the Terms of Use and Privacy Policy. You are not authorized to use this site if you do not agree to comply with the Terms of Use and Privacy Policy.

We may update our Terms of Use and Privacy Policy from time to time, and we will notify you of any changes by posting them on this page.

Contents of this site, including all site and section names, logos, graphics, images, presentation strategies, and other design elements, are covered by trademarks, copyrights, and other intellectual and trade property rights, held jointly or separately by the Center for Investigative Reporting. All rights are reserved. Authors may also hold rights to some material. Material on this site may not be copied, mirrored, cataloged, or displayed simultaneously with another site in part or in whole.

We respect the intellectual property of others. If you believe that your work has been copied — by us or by any third party on our site — in a manner that constitutes copyright infringement, please contact us.

###### Links and Frames

You may link to our site as long as the link does not cast us in a false or misleading light. You may not frame the content of our site. If you would like to license material from our site, please contact the Director of Finance and Administration at the Center for Investigative Reporting at administration@cironline.org.

###### Links to Other Websites

Our site may contain links to other websites that we think may be of interest to you. We have no control over these other sites or their content. You should be aware when you leave our site for another and remember that other sites are governed by their own user agreements and privacy policies, which you should be sure to read.

###### Your Comments on Our Content

We invite you to comment on our content as part of our interactive community.

You agree that your posted comments intended for display on our site (“Reader-Submitted Content”) will not include any content that is illegal, indecent, profane, threatening, defamatory, invasive of privacy or otherwise injurious to third parties; and that it will not consist of or contain software viruses, political campaigning, commercial solicitation, chain letters, mass mailings, obscenity or any form of “spam.” You may not use a false e-mail address, impersonate any person or entity, or otherwise mislead as to the origin of your Reader-Submitted Content.

You may not submit Reader-Submitted Content that infringes in any manner on the copyright, trademark or other intellectual property rights of any person or entity, or that contains any confidential or proprietary information of any person or entity, or that otherwise violates the legal rights of any person or entity. You may not submit Reader-Submitted Content that contains personally identifiable information about other people, such as their phone number, street address or e-mail address, or information about other people that could result in an invasion of their privacy or their harassment.

You agree that, by submitting any Reader-Submitted Content to us, you are granting to us a non-exclusive, royalty-free, perpetual, irrevocable and fully assignable and sublicensable right to use, reproduce, modify, adapt, publish, translate, edit, reformat, create derivative works from, distribute and display that Reader-Submitted Content throughout the world for any purpose and in any media. Your Reader-Submitted Content may be edited for length or clarity or for any other reason either before or after it is published, and it may be attributed it to you and may include your name and city. We reserve the right (but not the obligation) to remove any Reader-Submitted Content for any reason from our site.

###### California Watch’s use of the Echo commenting system and Echo Network

California Watch may participate in the Echo Network, which would make visitor content from other Echo sites available on California Watch and vice versa. 

Visitors agree that by posting content to any part of the California Watch site, they automatically grant, and represent and warrant that they have the right to grant, Echo a non-exclusive, royalty free, perpetual, irrevocable and fully assignable and sublicensable right to usethat content on all Echo sites that have opted into the Echo network.

###### AP News Registry

This Web site uses services provided by AP News Registry. AP News Registry collects content usage information and may use cookies in conjunction with this activity. Your continued readership of the Site means you accept the privacy policy of the AP News Registry. Please refer to the AP News Registry privacy policy at <http://www.apnewsregistry.com/privacycenter/servicepolicy.aspx> for further information. 

###### Privacy

We are committed to protecting your privacy. We have developed our site so that you can visit it without identifying yourself or revealing any personal information. Visitors to our site are not tracked as they access other sites; though we do analyze traffic on this site. We only collect personally identifying data about you, such as your name, address and e-mail address when you provide it to us voluntarily. California Watch notes and saves information such as time of day, browser type, browser language, and IP address for each visit to our site. We do not sell, trade, or otherwise transfer to outside parties your personally identifiable information. This does not include trusted third parties who assist us in operating our website, conducting our business, or servicing you, so long as those parties agree to keep this information confidential. We may also release your information when we believe release is appropriate to comply with the law, enforce our site policies, or protect ours or others’ rights, safety, or property. We may provide non-personally identifiable visitor information to other parties for marketing, advertising, or other uses.

###### How do we protect your information?

We implement a variety of security measures to maintain the safety of your personal information when you make a donation, or submit or post content.

We offer the use of a secure server on our transaction pages. All supplied sensitive information is transferred via Secure Socket Layer (SSL) technology and then encrypted into our payment gateway provider’s database only to be accessible by those authorized with special access rights to such systems, and are required to keep the information confidential.

After a transaction, your private information will not be stored on our servers.

###### Opt Out

If at any time you would like to unsubscribe from receiving future emails, we include detailed unsubscribe instructions at the bottom of each email.

###### COPPA Compliance

We are in compliance with the requirements of COPPA (Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act). We do not collect any information from anyone under 13 years of age. You must be over the age of 13 in order to receive information or comment on our site.

###### Termination

We reserve the right to terminate the site and this Terms of Use and Privacy Policy at any time without notice for any reason. The Limitation of Liability section of this Terms of Use and Privacy Policy shall survive any such termination.

###### Disclaimers and Limitation of Liability

ALTHOUGH WE TAKE REASONABLE STEPS TO PREVENT THE INTRODUCTION OF VIRUSES, WORMS, OR OTHER DESTRUCTIVE MATERIALS AND PROGRAMS TO OUR SITE, WE DO NOT GUARANTEE OR WARRANT THAT OUR SITE OR MATERIALS THAT MAY BE DOWNLOADED FROM OUR SITE ARE FREE FROM SUCH DESTRUCTIVE FEATURES. WE ARE NOT LIABLE FOR ANY DAMAGES OR HARM ATTRIBUTABLE TO SUCH FEATURES. WE ARE NOT LIABLE FOR ANY CLAIM, LOSS OR INJURY BASED ON ERRORS, OMISSIONS, INTERRUPTIONS OR OTHER INACCURACIES IN OUR SITE, NOR FOR ANY CLAIM, LOSS OR INJURY THAT RESULTS FROM YOUR USE OF THIS SITE OR YOUR BREACH OF ANY PROVISION OF THIS AGREEMENT.

###### Contact Us

If there are any questions regarding the Terms of Use and Privacy Policy you may contact us using the information below.

Center for Investigative Reporting  
2130 Center St., Suite 103  
Berkeley, CA 94704  
(510) 809-3160
